Rory Hartong-Redden

October 18, 2024 | Boulder, CO | roryhr@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/rory-hartong-redden | roryhr.com

Summary

Machine Learning Engineer with over 7 years of experience in data science, data engineering, statistical analysis, and software engineering. Core competencies: Python, ML, and statistical analysis, complemented by 3 years of management experience. Throughout my career I've focused on solving the right problem, understanding my data, writing excellent code, and being a good teammate.

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, SQL, R, Shell DevOps: AWS, Docker, CI/CD, Git, GitHub Data Processing: Postgres, Spark, Hadoop, S3, Airflow

Python Tools: pandas, scikit-learn, Flask, TensorFlow, PyTorch, PySpark, Matplotlib, Jupyter

Professional Experience

• Fast Radius (SyBridge)

Technical Manager and Senior Data Scientist

Boulder, CO

Aug 2021-May 2024

- Led a data science team of 3 through growth and scaling efforts, culminating in a successful IPO
- Ensured API uptime of our revenue-critical service, facilitating \$10M in monthly instant quotes
- Crafted SQL queries to collect data, monitor model accuracy, and answer business questions
- Trained and deployed a random forest regression model of CNC cycle time for CNC instant quoting, providing the majority of the revenue of our site
- Fast Radius Chicago, IL
 Data Scientist Feb 2020-Aug 2021
 - Tech stack: Python, Flask, Docker, AWS ECS, Datadog
 - As the founding data scientist and machine learning engineer I was responsible for building costing and quoting APIs that were backed by regression models
 - Predicted shipping costs using mixed integer programming to pack boxes for the UPS API
- runtastic Linz, Austria
 Data Engineer Oct 2018–Sep 2019
 - Tech stack: Python, SQL, Spark, Hadoop, Flume, Oozie, Hive
 - Led the design and deployment of a "People You Might Know" feature to bootstrap a social network and improve the retention rate
 - Built an ETL pipeline to anonymize customer data to comply with GDPR regulations
- Allstate Menlo Park, CA Research Analyst Jul 2016–Sep 2018
 - Tech stack: Python, pandas, TensorFlow, Spark, Julia, PostGIS, Keras
 - Trained machine learning models and analyzed telematics and crash data to predict risk
 - Co-authored a research paper titled "Real-time Prediction of Intermediate-Horizon Automotive Collision" with the Stanford Intelligent Systems Lab

Education

• University of California, Santa Barbara
MS Mechanical Engineering

Santa Barbara, CA Dec 2014

• University of California, Santa Barbara BS Physics & BS Mechanical Engineering Santa Barbara, CA June 2010